ALLAN DA SILVA PINTO

Ph.D. in Computer Science

@ allan.pinto@unicamp.br
Av. Albert Einstein, 1251, Campinas, SP, 13083-852
SP, Brazil

% http://www.recod.ic.unicamp.br/~allansp in https://www.linkedin.com/in/allansp84



EXPERIENCE

Teaching

Max Planck College

1 02/2012 - 07/2014

SP, Brazil

• Courses Taught: Computer Network, Computer Graphics, Compilers, Electrical Installations, Network Management.

University of Campinas

1 08/2019 - 12/2019

SP, Brazil

Course Taught: Computer Algorithms and Programming.

Research

The secret of playing football: Brazil versus the Netherlands

₩ 09/2019 - Ongoing

SP, Brazil

Research assistant (doctoral exchange program).

• Research topics: Data science, sports sciences, and machine learning.

Multi-Lingual Text Spotting and Recognition (MLTSR)

1 09/2018 - 09/2019

SP, Brazil

 Post-doctoral level research. Research topics: Computer vision and Machine learning.

DARPA Media Forensics (MediFor) Project

(1) 07/2016 - 07/2017

♥ Indiana, USA

- Research assistant (doctoral exchange program).
- Research topics: Provenance analysis, multimedia forensics, information retrieval, and computer vision.

Analysis of intrinsic and extrinsic properties of biometric samples for presentation attack detection

1 02/2014 - 09/2018

SP, Brazil

- Doctoral level research.
- Research topics: Information security; Computer vision; Image processing and analysis; and Biometrics.

A Countermeasure Method for Video-Based Face Spoofing Attacks

1 02/2011 - 10/2013

♀ SP, Brazil

- Master level research.
- Research topics: Information security; Computer vision; Image processing and analysis; and Biometrics.

Others

Refereed Journal Reviewer

🛗 2015 - Ongoing

• IEEE T-IFS, IEEE T-IP, IEEE Access, IEEE J-STSP, Elsevier PR, Elsevier PRL, Elsevier JVCI, Elsevier CVIU, among others.

Editorial Board Member

2019 - Ongoing

• Forensic Science International: Reports

SHORT BIO

I am a Postdoctoral Researcher at the University of Campinas (Unicamp), Brazil. I received a B.Sc. degree in Computer Science from the University of São Paulo (USP), Brazil, in 2011, an M.Sc. degree in Computer Science from the Unicamp, in 2013, and a Ph.D. degree also in Computer Science at the same university, in 2018. A part of my doctoral was accomplished at the University of Notre Dame, USA, in which I worked on different topics such as Presentation Attack Detection, Content-based Image Retrieval, and Multimedia Forensics.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

University of Campinas (Unicamp), Brazil

(1) 02/2014 - 09/2018

M.Sc. in Computer Science

University of Campinas (Unicamp), Brazil

1 02/2011 - 10/2013

B.Sc. in Computer Science

University of São Paulo (USP), Brazil

1 02/2007 - 02/2011

SCIENTIFIC PRODUCTION

Journal Articles	10
Book Chapters	3
• Conference Proceedings Papers	10
Conference Proceedings Abstracts	1

AWARDS



2019 CAPES Best Computer Science Thesis Award

Best Computer Science Ph.D. Thesis in

2019 IC/Unicamp Thesis and Dissertation
Contest

Best Computer Science Ph.D. Thesis.

STRENGTHS

Machine Learning Computer vision

Digital Forensics Biometrics

Sports Science C/C++ Python

LANGUAGES

Portuguese English

